Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Louis Weiss, Mar 15, 1983; cuid1564 (Box 10, Cassette 384 A-B, Box 30, Cd L. Weiss 1-2)
    Interview includes discussion of Weiss' emigration from Poland, his work as a dress presser, and activities of the The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
    Interview also includes commentary from an unidentified woman and unidentified man. The woman speaks to her experience in different progressive and radical organizations during the 1930s-1940s, including the International Labor Defense, American Labor Party, and others.
  - Sam Weiss, Apr 8, 1980; cuid1565 (Box 30, Cd S. Weiss 1, Box 79, Cassette 271)
    Interview documents the role of the Freie Arbeter Shtimme (Free Voice of Labor) in the labor movement of the 1920s-1930s and describes activities of anarchists within the Arbeter Ring (Workmens' Circle).
  - Saul Wellman - Transcript, Aug 24, 1972; cuid1566 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Interview covers the activities of the Communist Party during the 1930s-1950s, Wellman's reflections on the relationship between the Communist Party and unions, Communists and United Auto Workers during the Second World War, reactions to the Hitler-Stalin Pact, and the Left's activities during the Cold War.
  - Saul Wellman: 65th birthday dinner, 1980; cuid1567 (Box 79, Cassette 273 A-B, Box 30, Cd Wellman dinner 1-3)
    Duration: 144 minutes in two parts
  - Yvette West, Jan 19, 1983; cuid1568 (Box 30, Cd West 1-2, Box 79, Cassette 275 A-B)
    Interview covers West's family dynamics growing up, her youth in the International Workers of the World (IWW) during the mid-1930s, and the literary career of her father, Yiddish critic B. Rivkin.
  - Ed Wiese, Apr 24, 1981; cuid1569 (Box 79, Cassette 274 A-B, Box 30, Cd Wiese 1-2)
    Interview covers Wiese's work in the Westinghouse Elevator Plant in Jersey City and the influence of the left. It also documents his time as president of Local 456 of the United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America (UE).
  - Jim Williams, Apr 2, 1970; cuid1570 (Box 30, Cd Williams 1, Box 79, Cassette 276)
    Interview regarding the internal politics and activities of Students for a Democratic Society on campuses across the United States. Williams also comments on reasons for the SDS split and the different Marxist factions in the New Left.
  - Paul W. Williams - Transcript, May 11, 1976; cuid1571 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Interview documents the prosecution of International Workers' Order during the 1950s.
  - Tim Wohlforth - Transcript, Aug 29, 1976; cuid1572 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Interview documents Wohlforth's background in Bridgeport, Connecticut during the 1930s-1940s and Socialism and Trotskyism during the 1950s.
  - Alice Dodge Wolfson, Apr 1, 1982; cuid1573 (Box 79, Cassette 279, Box 30, Cd Wolfson 1, Box 9, Folder 5)
    Interview documents the activities of the League for Industrial Democracy, the Office Workers Union, the New England CIO, and the Socialist Party during the 1930s.
  - Workers Party/Standing Fast Conference, May 6, 1983 - May 7, 1983; cuid1574 (Box 30, Cd Workers Party 1-8, Box 79, Cassette 280 A-H)
    Recording of an event commemorating the opening of the Max Shachtman Papers at the Tamiment Library. Panel presentations on 1) the character and activities of the Workers Party, 1940-49 2) Harvey Swados' novel Standing Fast, based on the WP, and 3) three magazines with roots in the WP, Politics, Dissent, and New Politics. Speakers include Herman Benson, Ricky Flanders, Albert Glotzer, Julius Jacobson, Irving Sanes, Morton Clurman, Paul Cowan, Lewis Coser, Robert Cummings, and Phyllis Jacobson.
  - Frederick Wright, Jun 20, 1984; cuid1575 (Box 30, Cd Wright 1-2, Box 9, Folder 6, Box 79, Cassette 281 A-B)
    Transcript available, Box 2
    Wright describes the background of his family and his grandfather's influence on his drawing, his work as a clip-joint musician during the 1920s, going to sea during the 1930s, his work as freelance cartoonist for National Maritime Union (NMU), the Cold War, and his work for the UE News.
  - Fannie Yellin, Apr 16, 1980; cuid1576 (Box 79, Cassette 282, Box 30, Cd Yellin 1)
    Yellin describes the anarchist circle in Philadelphia during the 1910s, the personality and ideas of Rudolf Rocker, and the role of the Rocker Circle in Los Angeles in publishing Rocker's work and facilitating his speaking tours.
  - Karl Yoneda, Jan 7, 1983; cuid1577 (Box 30, Cd Yoneda 1, Box 9, Folder 7, Box 79, Cassette 283)
    Interview documents the Japanese-American Communist movement in the 1920s-1930s, the Japanese-language press in the 1920s and early 1930s, sectarian errors, cultural events, role in labor movement and opposition to the concentration camps that incarcerated Japanese-Americans during World War II, the Popular Front in the Japanese-American Left, and the state of Asian-American labor in the 1980s.
  - Vincent Young, Aug 4, 1983; cuid1578 (Box 79, Cassette 284 A-B, Box 30, Cd Young 1-3)
    Discussion includes Young's youth in New York during the 1920s-1930s, his involvement in a black masonic lodge, and the activities of the Congress of Radical Equality (CORE) in Brooklyn during the 1940s-1960s. Other topics include the Downstate Medical Center, New York World's Fair demonstrations, and housing issues in Brooklyn in the 1980s.
  - Mary Zackheim, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1579 (Box 79, Cassette 285 A-B, Box 30, Cd Mary Zackheim 1-2)
    Interview includes stories about Moshe Nadir and other Jewish literary personalities, Zackheim's philosophies on life, and Zackheim's thoughts on the Communist Party. Second portion of interview is not not Mary Zackheim. It is an unidentified man speaking about Communist Party involvement in a strike.
    Duration: 30 minutes in two parts
  - Meyer Zackheim, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1580 (Box 79, Cassette 286.5, Box 30, Cd Meyer Zackheim 1)
    Interview covers the activities of the New York Left in the 1910s-1920s and the problems of the Jewish progressive movement in Miami Beach in the 1970s.
  - Meyer Zackheim, Abe Glassman, Florence Glassman, Ben Kliger, and Rosenfeld, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1581 (Box 30, Cd Zackheim, Glassmans, Klieger & Rosenfeld 1, Box 79, Cassette 286)
    This group interview, taken in Miami Beach, Florida, collects members' recollections of the progressive Jewish cultural movement in the 1920s-1940s. Topics discussed include how narrators became involved in the movement, trade union activism (especially in the needle trades), strikes, the Workmen's Circle, the Morgen Freiheit, Jewish theatre, music and theatre clubs, and factional divisions on the left.
  - Meyer Zackheim, Archie Rothenberg & Rose Lipshitz, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1582 (Box 79, Cassette 287.5, Box 30, Cd Zackheim, Rothenberg & Lipshitz 1)
    Interview regarding the relationship of culture and the Jewish progressive movement. Rose Lipshitz discusses the challenges of immigrant women in America of 1920s and the appeal of the Left. Archie Rothenberg discusses political activities of Jewish Left in 1920s-1930s. Additional topics covered include lectures, union activism in garment and millinery trades, women's roles in trade union and Left political organizations, the Bund and labor activities in Poland, the destruction of Eastern European Jewish communities during the Holocaust, and Yidisher Kultur Farband (YKUF) reading circles.
  - Meyer Zackheim, Ed Weiss, Julius Silver, and Sylvia Silver, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1583 (Box 30, Cd Zackheim, Weiss & Silvers 1-2, Box 79, Cassette 287 A-B)
    Group interview concerning the relationship of Jewish culture and left movements in the first decades of the twentieth century. Topics include immigration following the 1905 Russian Revolution, the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU), needle trade strikes, the founding of the Yidisher Kultur Farband (YKUF), political orientations within YKUF, the Morgen Freiheit, the role of women in the YKUF and garment unions, Jewish choruses, the concentration of left activities in Chicago in the early twentieth century, German-American socialist organizations compared with Jewish organizations, the Communist Party's relationship with culture, and the Soviet Union. Group likely also contains Mary Zackheim.
    Duration: 124 minutes over two parts
  - Joseph Zawadowski, Jul 28, 1983; cuid1584 (Box 30, Cd Zawadowski 1-2, Box 79, Cassette 288 A-B)
    Interview documents the activities of the Polish-American Left in Chicago from the time of his father (1920s) to the 1980s and Zawadowski's own experiences in the Spanish Civil War.
    Duration: 124 minutes in two parts
  - Steve Zeluck, Dec 15, 1982; cuid1585 (Box 30, Cd Zeluck 1, Box 79, Cassette 289)
    Interview covers the Johnson-Forest Tendency, Trotskyism in Philadephia and Chicago, and Zeluck's reflections on C.L.R. James.
  - Steve Zeluck, undated; cuid1586 (Box 10, Cassette 410, Box 30, Cd Zeluck 2)
    Interview includes discussion of the Johnson-Forest Tendency, CLR James, and the Socialist Workers Party.
  - Charles Zimmerman, Oct 31, 1974; cuid1587 (Box 30, Cd Zimmerman 1-2, Box 6, Cassette 290 A-B, Box 9, Folder 8)
    Interview documents the activities of the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the struggle between left and right in the 1910s-1920s.
  - Celia Lewis Zitron - Transcript, May 8, 1976; cuid1588 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Interview documents the activities of the New York Teachers Union during the 1940s.
    Interview by Glenn Goldstein.
- Fred Zimring Interviews, 1976-1978
  This series contains interviews conducted by Fred R. Zimring as part of the research for his doctoral dissertation, "McCarthyism, the Cold War, and Temple University: the Dismissal of Professor Barrows Dunham from Temple," completed in pursuit of his degree from Teachers College, Columbia University in 1982.
  These transcripts are copies from the Barrows Dunham-Fred Zimring Collection in the Conwellana-Templana Collection at Temple University Libraries.
  Arrangement
  Master copies are housed in boxes 91 and 92. User copies are housed in boxes 73 and 74.
  - Aptheker, Herbert, Jul 5, 1977; cuid200 (Box 30, Cd Apetheker 1, Box 73, Audiocassette 1, Box 92)
  - Boudin, Leonard, Oct 16, 1976; cuid201 (Box 30, Cd Boudin 1, Box 73, Audiocassette 4, Box 92)
  - Edelman, Arthur, Feb 4, 1977; cuid202 (Box 30, Cd Edelman 1, Box 73, Audiocassette 11, Box 92)
  - Huganir, George, September 21, 1976 (Box 92, Audiocassette 18D)
  - LeRoy, Gaylord, Mar 12, 1977; cuid203 (Box 30, Cd LeRoy 2, Box 74, Audiocassette 23A, Box 92)
  - LeRoy, Gaylord, Aug 15, 1976; cuid204 (Box 30, Cd LeRoy 1, Box 74, Audiocassette 23B, Box 92)
    Scope and Contents
    Original cassette tape had sticky shed syndrome. Although the cassette was able to be digitized after baking, there are still transport squeaking noices heard in the files.
- Reynold Hills Project Interviews, 1980-1981; cuid1593
  Interviewees were members of a small colony in upstate New York, which grew from a club called Followers of the Trail. The colony was created by Eastern European Jewish garment workers as a hiking camp for physical exercise and political discussion.
- Filmmakers' Tapes and Transcripts
  - Seeing Red, 1978-1981; cuid1594
    This subseries contains interviews contributing to a film on American Communism during the 1930s-1950s by Julia Reichert and James Klein of Heartland Productions.
  - The Life and Times of Rosie the Riveter, 1976-1979; cuid1595
    These interviews were largely taken between 1976-1977 to contribute to a film about women production workers during World War II by Connie Field of Clarity Productions.
  - A Crime to Fit the Punishment, 1975-1981
    Interviews from the film A Crime Fit to the Punishment by Barbara Moss and Steve Mack of Moss Productions regarding the making of a film regarding the making of the ealier film Salt of the Earth in 1953-1954.
    - Chacon, Juan, cuid205 (Box 72, Audiocassette 46, Box 30, Cd Chacon 1)
    - Chacon, Virginia & Angie Sanchez, May 21, 1976; cuid206 (Box 72, Audiocassette 47A, 47B, Box 30, Cd Chacon/Sanchez 1-2)
    - Jencks, Clint, Feb 15, 1975; cuid208 (Box 72, Audiocassette 49A, 49B, 49C, 49D, Box 30, Cd Jencks 1)
    - Jencks, Clint & Juan Chacon, cuid207 (Box 72, Audiocassette 50A-50B, Box 30, Cd Jencks/Chacon 1-2)
    - Scherwin, Jules, November 11, 1975 (Box 72, Audiocassette 52A, 52B, 52A (copy), 52B (copy))
    - Scherwin, Jules, April 9, 1981 (Box 72, Audiocassette 53A, 53B, 53C)
    - Williams, Henrietta, May 21, 1976 (Box 72, Audiocassette 54A, 54B)
  - Tighten Your Belts, Bite the Bullet, 1976-1979; cuid1596
    This subseries contains interviews supporting a film by John Miller of City Crisis Film Group regarding the political and social effects of the mid-1970s urban budget crises in New York and Cleveland.
  - Anarchism in America, 1967-1981; cuid1597
    Interviews supporting the documentary Anarchism in America by Joel Sucher and Steve Fischler of Pacific Street Films regarding the history and character of anarchism.
  - Free Voice of Labor, 1976-1979; cuid1598
    Interviews supporting the documentary Free Voice of Labor by Joel Sucher and Steve Fischler of Pacific Street Films regarding the Yiddish-language anarchist newspaper Freie Arbeter Stimme (Free Voice of Labor), published from the 1880s-1970s.
  - Trouble on Fashion Avenue, 1981; cuid1599
    Interviews supporting the documentary Trouble on Fasion Avenue by Claude Beller of TV Documentary Arts Projects, Inc. Interviewees speak about the history of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and radicalism within the union.
  - The Case of the Legless Veteran: James Kutcher, 1977; cuid1600
    Interviews supporting the documentary The Case of the Legless Veteran: James Kutcher by Howard Petrick regarding the legal battles of James Kutcher, a World War II veteran from whom the United States government attempted to deny benefits due to his affiliation with the Socialist Workers Party.
  - Peekskill Work in Progress, 1979-1980
    This subseries contains interviews taken by Barbara Kopple of Cabin Creek Films.
    - Patterson, Bill and Louise, January 10, 1979; cuid43077
      - Audio, cuid43077A (Box 75, Audiocassette cuid43077A)
        Duration: 75 minutes; Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.
      - Audio, cuid43077B (Box 75, Audiocassette cuid43077B)
        Duration: 75 minutes.
    - Danis, Sid, October 8, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 3)
    - Marcus, Heshie, April 27, 1979 or 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 5)
    - Silverman, Sol, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 8A)
    - Tarantel, Al, January 24, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 10)
    - Ferris, Mr. and Mrs. Richard, undated (Box 85, Audiocassette 13B)
    - Naylor, Colin, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 14)
    - Tuttle, Jack, October 23, 1979 or 1980 (Box 85, Audiocassette 18)
    - Walsh, John, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 19)
    - Hambro, Lee, November 11, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 20)
    - Hayes, Lee, undated (Box 85, Audiocassette 21A, 21B, 21C)
    - Seeger, Pete and Toshi, January 24, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 24A, 24B)
    - Silber, Sylvia, December 2, 1972; cuid43163 (Box 85, Audiocassette 25)
      Preservation note: Poor audio quality
    - Silber, Irwin, February 23, undated; cuid43164 (Box 85, Audiocassette 26)
    - Brown, Lloyd, April 5, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 27B)
    - Foner, Henry, April 4, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 28)
    - Foner, Phil, undated (Box 85, Audiocassette 29A, 29B, 29C)
    - Naison, Mark, undated (Box 85, Audiocassette 30A, 30C)
    - Siegel, Jeff, February 16, 1979 or 1980 (Box 85, Audiocassette 32A)
    - Tabb, Bill, March 15, 1979 or 1980 (Box 85, Audiocassette 33A, 33B)
    - Ward, Doug, January 16, 1979; cuid1052 (Box 30, Cd cuid1052, Box 85, Audiocassette 34)
      Origial Format: 1/8" Audiocassette, Duration: 20 min.
    - Tapley, Mel, January 16, 1979 (Box 85, Audiocassette 50)
    - Backer, Leon et al, July 5, 1979 or 1980 (Box 85, Audiocassette 51B)
    - Shines, Ralph, January 16, 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 39)
    - Levey, Herbert, July 22, 1979 or 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 42)
    - Levey, Herbert, January 15, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 42)
    - Mercadel, Kevin, Feb 27, 1979; cuid1053 (Case Audio Cabinet 1, Drawer 1, Cassette cuid1053, Box 30, Cd cuid1053)
      Original Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 57 min.
    - Cook, Marvel, January 9, 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 44)
    - Hicks, James, March 9, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 45)
    - Lapolla, Ray, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 46)
    - Moscow, Warren, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 47)
    - Rowe, Billy, 1979-05-02 (Box 75, Audiocassette 48)
    - Stolley, Richard, 1979-1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 49)
    - Eisner, Norman, April 26, 1979 or 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 52)
    - Goldstein, Burt, May 5, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 54)
    - Lubell, Dave, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 57)
    - Marcus, Sidney, July 10, 1979 or 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 58, 58B)
    - Neuchow, Bill and Taylor, January 9, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 60A)
    - Goodman, George et al, August 29, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 61)
    - Baker, Sarah T., undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 64)
    - DeSantos, Lou and wife, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 67A, 67B)
    - Glassberg, Bert, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 68)
    - Hersh, Ben, December 30, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 69A, 69B)
    - Hobson, Frances, June 8, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 70)
    - Jamison, Willis, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 71)
    - Kroph, Norman, 1979 (Box 75, Audiocassette 72)
    - Levenson, Gene, undated (Box 75, Audiocassette 73)
    - Overstreet, Fred, October 23, 1979 or 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 74A, 74B)
    - Poritzky, Ben, October 21, 1979 or 1980 (Box 75, Audiocassette 76)
    - Rick, Chester R., August 3, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 78)
    - Smith, Coleman, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 81)
    - Baker, Fred, December 20, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 85A, 85B, 85C)
    - Bauman, Irma and Marty, March 22, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 86)
    - Eisenberg, Alex, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 87)
    - Fine, Danny and June Fisher, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 88A, 88a, 88a)
    - Payne, Anita, May 5, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 89)
    - Lynn, Conrad, February 11, 1980 (Box 82, Audiocassette 90A, 90B)
    - Brody, Pauline, October 23, 1979 or 1980 (Box 82, Audiocassette 94A, 94B)
    - Cohen, Abe, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 95)
    - Colman, Abbie and Morris, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 96)
    - Feinstein, Allan and Mary, January 11, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 97)
    - Ford, Calvin, May 8, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 98)
    - Horn, Nora, May 13, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 99)
    - Levenson, Yasha and Flo, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 102)
    - Reibman, Svi, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 104)
    - Rock, Pauline, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 105)
    - Rossman, Barbara, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 106)
    - Schwartz, Goldie and Walter, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 109A, 109B)
    - Shappes, Morris, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 111)
    - Steck, Bob, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 112)
    - Froman, Jay, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 113)
    - Salzberg, Norman and Dan, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 114A, 114B)
    - Herwill, Claire, 1979 (Box 82, Audiocassette 115A, 115B, 115C, 115D)
    - Sverdlow, Amy, undated (Box 82, Audiocassette 116)
    - Schwartz, Tony, undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 117)
    - Hock, Lumis V., undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 118)
    - Hunter, Bernie, September 17, 1979 (Box 84, Audiocassette 119)
    - Scivoletto, John, October 27, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 120)
    - Franrovitch, Alan, undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 122)
    - Kaufman, Dr. Maurice, September 3, 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 123A, 123B)
    - Slochower, Dr., March 19, 1979 (Box 84, Audiocassette 124A, 124B)
    - Script Meeting, November 1, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125A, 125B)
    - Script Meeting, March 7,1979 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125C)
    - Script Meeting, 1979-03-19 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125D, 125E, 125F, 125G, 125H, 125I)
    - Script Meeting, February 26, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125J)
    - Script Meeting, undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 125L)
    - Script Meeting, February 22, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125M)
    - Script Meeting, January 30, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125N)
    - Script Meeting, January 23, 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125O, 125P, 125Q)
    - Script Meeting, April 9, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 125R)
    - Resnick, Ephraim, June 28, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 126)
    - Peery, Nelson, 1980-08-20 (Box 84, Audiocassette 127A)
    - Shields, Art, undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 128)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 130)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 131)
    - Moliti, Vito, February 18, 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 132)
    - Fischer, Steven, September 17, 1979 or 1980 (Box 84, Audiocassette 133)
    - Kopple, Barbara (and Misc), undated (Box 84, Audiocassette 135)
  - Columbia Student Strike of 1968, undated; cuid1601
    This subseries contains eight interviews regarding the 1968 student strike at Columbia University.
  - Transcripts of Completed Films, undated; cuid1602
    This subseries contains transcripts of three completed films: Miles of Smiles, Years of Struggle by Paul Wagner, With Babies and Bannners by Lorraine Gray, and The Wobblies by Deborah Shaffer and Stewart Bird.
- Tamiment Institute Tapes, circa 1955-1965
  This series contains a collection of tapes held by the Tamiment Institute that predated the establishment of the Oral History of the American Left. These tapes include recordings of meetings, speeches, panel discussions, and interviews recorded during the 1950s-1960s.
  - "Memorial Meeting" Brazier, Dick, et al., November 18, 1960 (Box 89, Audiocassette 1A, 1B, 1C, 1D, Box 83)
  - Judge Jacob Panken, Jun 21, 1960; cuid1607 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 2, Box 89)
    Recording regarding Meyer London.
  - A. Philip Randolph, undated; cuid1608
    Recording of a speech.
    - Access audiocassette (Box 83, Audiocassette 3)
    - Master audiocassette, cuid43202 (Box 89, Audiocassette 3)
      Duration: 16 minutes
    - Open reel audio (Box 42)
  - Upton Sinclair, Oct 15, 1958; cuid1611 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 4, Box 89)
    Speech at a League for Industrial Democracy Meeting.
  - Trachtenberg, undated (Box 83, Audiocassette 5, Box 89)
  - Bertram Wolfe, Jul 12, 1960; cuid1618 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 6, Box 89)
    Recording of a speech titled "Has the Soviet Union Changed?"
  - Tamiment Discussion with the Children of Norman Thomas, 1959; cuid1615 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 7A, 7B, Box 89)
  - Harry Fleischman regarding Norman Thomas, Apr 23, 1964; cuid1605 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 8, Box 89)
    Harry Fleischman on Norman Thomas: A Biography.
  - Norman Thomas, 1964; cuid1614 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 9A, 9B, Box 89)
    Recording of Speech titled "The Politics of Peace."
  - Norman Thomas, Nov 14, 1956; cuid1613 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 10, Box 89)
  - Clarence and Ruth Senior on Norman Thomas, Feb 4, 1962; cuid1609 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 11, Box 89)
  - Anna Strunsky Walling, Jun 27, 1960 and Jul 19, 1960; cuid1616 (Box 42, Box 25, Cd Walling 1-4, Box 83, Audiocassette 12A, 12B, Box 89)
    This interview was originally taken as part of a Tamiment Institute oral history series.
    Interview by Melvin Drimmer and Melvyn Dubofsky.
  - Industrial Workers of the World, Apr 11, 1959; cuid1606 (Box 42, Box 83, Audiocassette 13A, 13B, Box 89)
    Tamiment Institute discussion, including a memorial meeting featuring speakers Dick Brazier, Herbert Mahler, and Sam Weiner.